foreign
good morning everyone today I'm
harvesting Treasures from my garden and
enjoying the late spring I'm a little
sad it will be summer soon but I will be
outdoors as much as possible until then
fruits
[Music]
in the process of making this video I
actually created enormous mess in my
kitchen and so I wanted to share a bit
about my relationship with chaos for
those who might be able to relate
to begin with I used to be an incredibly
messy person and in many ways I still am
if I'm not mindful the day can quickly
fall apart into a whirlwind of chaos
starting multiple projects all at once
and finding myself surrounded by an
enormous mess at the end of the day
consequently I will have days where I'm
too exhausted to do much of anything
because I burn myself out and if you
think I look quite put together in these
videos that's great because that is my
intention I'm always trying to be a
little more put together and improving
my tendency towards getting distracted
and lost in a hundred different tasks
laughs
[Music]
foreign
these videos have helped me slowly
improve and learn how to practice deep
focus on projects and be mindful with
each step and take things slowly
initially I was quite contrary to my
innate nature but now I've come to find
great peace in Solace and slowing down
it has reduced my stress and I've
permanently changed due to putting into
practice a slower simpler daily pace I
can't imagine giving into the frenzied
Whirlwind of activity I used to partake
in of course this is only my personal
experience that doesn't mean that
there's anything wrong with you if
you're highly distractible and get lost
in projects I can relate and it's part
of who I am but in my case it was making
my life more stressful so I had to reel
myself back in celebrating my
chaotically artistic Soul while also
developing a layer of self-awareness and
mindfulness that would help me function
in daily life a little easier
particularly slowing down in order to
gently go about the tasks that need
doing in order for me to feel more at
ease so I can enjoy my more creative
side with greater freedom
now I take joy in spending time taking
care of my space and cleaning up after
myself I've discovered a love of taking
care of my home and it helped me become
more positive and peaceful
I feel that homes have a specific
atmosphere when you walk into them that
goes beyond the physical in places full
of love and laughter I have felt that
love when I enter them I cannot explain
this but I do know that we connect our
memories and our experiences to our
surroundings if we've experienced a lot
of turmoil in a place it continues to
feel that way over time it's almost as
if your space reflects you both in
literal and slightly more mysterious
ways for example I noticed I was using a
lot of negative self-talk when I was in
my kitchen because I tend to get grumpy
because I despise cleaning the kitchen I
love to clean every other part of my
house but I do not enjoy the kitchen I
think at least a few of you can relate
so I decided I would try to change
things I tried being more positive
turning on Pleasant music and focusing
on making good memories through cooking
with friends or baking my favorite
treats
thank you
foreign
[Music]
practicing a deep appreciation for my
shelter food and memories I have in
regards to my space can help me feel
more satisfied with how things are not
focused on how they could be it's so
easy to see pictures online of Home
Spaces that are beautiful but just not
practical for your interests or
lifestyle be true to what works for you
makes it the easiest for you to clean
and helps you just feel lighter when
you're there the mindset shift sometimes
makes all the difference on its own
[Music]
foreign
I was so happy to be able to harvest so
much mint so soon this year it is not
the perfect time to harvest them but I
was in need of a lot more tea so I
decided to go ahead and take them as
they're going to keep a regrowing and
I'm probably going to be able to get
several more harvests before it gets too
cold so I'm going to tie these up and
hang them up to dry I also made some
lilac infused honey which is delicious
if you have lilacs there are so many
recipes you can make with them I have
made tea and rice pudding and all sorts
of things with lilac I've even made
lilac syrup I'm gonna have some of this
on toast right now and in several weeks
it will be far more infused and far more
tasty but yes as you can see Miss Bianca
is joining me in the creation of this
week's video she is a very dedicated
actress and she's enjoying her
Wildflower crab own I picked a bowl of
lettuce for her because she usually
likes lettuce but um she just sat in it
she didn't eat it at all she was much
more interested in the dandelions I also
found several morel mushrooms and a
neighbor gave me a lot more and so I'm
going to dehydrate these to use later
because right now I'm not quite in the
mood for mushrooms but I think I will
get into that once the fall comes one
thing I like to do is take a small
amount of mint and put some essential
oils on them usually peppermint or
Citrus and then I hang them up and then
they help the house smell really nice so
I'm gonna get started and I highly
recommend all of you to keep an eye out
for mint maybe even wild mint because it
is all over the place right now
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
my home has been undergoing many changes
I love to decorate and I'm ever changing
things about but I do make sure to try
to keep things simple enough for me to
upkeep and I'm sure we'll simplify it
even more as my life changes
I also like to remember that homes are
supposed to look like they've been lived
in I cannot fathom the amount of cat and
dog hair I have on my floor at any given
moment but I try to remember that it's
just a consequence of having love and
life in my home and that is worth it
I hope you enjoyed this week's
Expeditions out in the garden looking
for all sorts of herbs the herbs that
I've been growing this year are not
quite ready but a lot of these more wild
varieties that I have planted have been
doing quite well and so I was just so
excited to bring in some of those fresh
Botanical smells into my home especially
when I harvest and dry Mint or Sage it
is just such a wonderful smell so I've
been really enjoying it and I think it's
going to definitely help me feel a lot
more peaceful and meditative in my space
hello Mia I think Bianca wants to join
us I have lived in a lot of different
places growing up in so many different
types of homes and living arrangements
I've even done some apartments that were
very unsafe unfortunately for the sake
of trying to save some money when I was
quite a bit younger all those
experiences I think taught me how
important it is to fill your home with
love and kind words and kind thoughts
family or friends or maybe just the
company of loving animals and plants and
I think that all those things have the
greatest impact on your home space it's
not the things you have in it I highly
encourage you to keep an eye out for
wild mint dandelions lilacs maybe if you
are in a place with abundant nature if
not there are a lot of places you can
purchase herbs to experiment with or
grow them yourself on a windowsill it is
such a fun and mindful hobby I think
well then we are going to finish our
lilac tea and then we are going to go on
some more Adventures pick up some more
lettuce for Bernard because I'm sure he
is quite hungry and you ate all the
lettuce didn't you there's just none
left for him oh my goodness
oh my goodness thank you again for all
the support of my Etsy shop and all the
new art pieces I've released this year I
have been working on some new designs
and always appreciate your ideas and
your input and I'm sending you so much
love and I will see you very soon
goodbye
foreign
[Music]